<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!--TEST DDI1.2.2 XML DOCUMENT(GENERATED FROM UKDA NESSTAR XML RECORD FOR STUDY NUMBER 7724).
CONTAINS ALL ELEMENTS/ATTRIBUTES REFERENCED BY FOR CDC 1.2.2 PROFILE
PLUS ADDITIONAL ELEMENTS/ATTRIBUTES THAT ARE NOT REQUIRED FOR THE PROFILE
Darren Bell 01 May 2020-->
<codeBook xml-lang="en" xmlns="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI http://www.icpsr.umich.edu/DDI/Version1-2-2.xsd">
    <docDscr>
        <citation>
            <titlStmt>
                <titl xml-lang="en">DDI 1.2.2 XML Document for Study 7724</titl>
            </titlStmt>
            <holdings xml-lang="en"
                URI="https://beta.ukdataservice.ac.uk/datacatalogue/studies/study?id=7724"/>
        </citation>
    </docDscr>
    <stdyDscr>
        <citation>
            <titlStmt>
                <titl xml-lang="en"> European Quality of Life Time Series, 2007 and 2011: Open
                    Access </titl>
                <parTitl xml-lang="de">Deutsche Titel zum Beispiel</parTitl>
                <IDNo xml-lang="en" agency="UKDA">7724</IDNo>
            </titlStmt>
            <rspStmt>
                <AuthEnty xml-lang="en" affiliation="University of Essex">A N Other</AuthEnty>
            </rspStmt>
            <distStmt>
                <distrbtr xml-lang="en" abbr="UKDA">UK Data Archive</distrbtr>
                <distDate date="2020-01-01T00:00:00Z">Jan 2020</distDate>
            </distStmt>
        </citation>
        <stdyInfo>
            <subject>
                <keyword xml-lang="en" vocab="ELSST" vocabURI="optional for future use"
                    >HEALTH</keyword>
                <topcClas xml-lang="en" vocab="CESSDA Topic Classification"
                    vocabURI="urn:ddi:int.cessda.cv:TopicClassification:4.0">HEALTH</topcClas>
            </subject>
            <abstract xml-lang="en"> Abstract copyright UK Data Service and data collection
                copyright owner.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; This dataset spanning 2 years of the
                &lt;i&gt;European Quality of Life Survey&lt;/i&gt; (EQLS) was prepared as open data,
                originally for the UK Data Service’s first App Challenge in summer 2015. It is a
                harmonised subset of variables taken from the larger &lt;a
                href="http://discover.ukdataservice.ac.uk/Catalogue/?sn=7348" target="_new" &gt;
                EQLS Integrated Data File&lt;/a&gt; (SN 7348).&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; The
                &lt;i&gt;European Quality of Life Survey&lt;/i&gt; (EQLS) is one of a number of key
                surveys carried out by the &lt;i&gt;European Foundation for the Improvement of
                Living and Working Conditions&lt;/i&gt; (Eurofound), a European Union Agency that
                was established in 1975 to contribute to the planning and design of better living
                and working conditions. Eurofound carries out its role in partnership with
                governments, employers, trade unions and the European Union institutions.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;br&gt; The EQLS is a unique, pan-European survey that examines both the
                objective circumstances of European citizens' lives and how they feel about those
                circumstances and their lives in general. It looks at a range of issues, such as
                employment, income, education, housing, family, health and work-life balance. It
                also looks at subjective topics, such as people's levels of happiness, how satisfied
                they are with their lives, and how they perceive the quality of their
                societies.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Carried out every four years since 2003, the survey
                collects data on a range of issues, such as employment, income, education, housing,
                family, health and work-life balance. It also looks at subjective topics, such as
                people's levels of happiness, life satisfaction, and perceived quality of society.
                Over the years, the EQLS has developed into a valuable set of indicators which
                complements traditional indicators of economic growth and living standard such as
                GDP or income. These offer a unique source of comparative information on the quality
                of living and working conditions across the EU. The EQLS indicators are more
                inclusive of environmental and social aspects of progress and therefore are easily
                integrated into the decision-making process and taken up by public debate at EU and
                national levels in the European Union.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; By running the survey
                regularly, it has also become possible to track key trends in the quality of
                people's lives over time and gain deeper insight in the issues central to European
                policy. The results provide a strong basis for policy makers to identify
                opportunities for improvement and to develop forward looking perspectives. Previous
                surveys have shown, for instance, that people are having greater difficulty making
                ends meet since the economic crisis began. In many countries, they also feel that
                there is now more tension between people from different ethnic groups. And across
                Europe, people now trust their governments less than they did before. However,
                people still continue to get the greatest satisfaction from their family life and
                personal relationships.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; Further information about the survey
                can be found on the &lt;i&gt;European Foundation for the Improvement of Living and
                Working Conditions&lt;/i&gt; (Eurofound) &lt;a
                href="http://www.eurofound.europa.eu/areas/qualityoflife/eqls/index" target="_new"
                &gt; EQLS&lt;/a&gt; web pages.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; In each wave a sample of adult
                population is selected randomly for a face-to-face interview. In view of the
                prospective European enlargements the geographical coverage of the survey has
                expanded over time from 28 countries in 2003 to 34 countries in 2011-12.&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;First EQLS in 2003 - 28 countries: 27 EU Member States and
                Turkey&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Second EQLS in 2007-2008 - 31 countries: 27 EU Member
                States, Croatia, FYR Macedonia, Turkey and Norway&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Third EQLS in
                2011-2012 - 34 countries: 27 EU Member States and Croatia, Iceland, FYR Macedonia,
                Montenegro, Serbia, Turkey and Kosovo.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt; This open
                subset contains 195 variables from two years, 2007 and 2011-12, 3 weights, and the
                full number of cases, almost 80,000.&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;B&gt;Main
                Topics&lt;/B&gt;:&lt;br&gt;The survey covers multiple dimensions of quality of life:
                employment and work-life balance, income and deprivation, housing and local
                environment, family and social contacts, health and mental wellbeing, subjective
                wellbeing (e.g. happiness, life satisfaction), social exclusion, perceived quality
                of society (e.g. tensions, trust in institutions) as well as access to and perceived
                quality of public services. </abstract>
            <sumDscr>
                <collDate date="2007" event="start"
                    cycle="Wave Two: 2007-2008; Wave Three: 2011-2012"/>
                <collDate date="2012" event="end" cycle="Wave Two: 2007-2008; Wave Three: 2011-2012"/>
                <nation xml-lang="en" abbr="FR"> France</nation>
                <nation xml-lang="en" abbr="GB"> United Kingdom</nation>
                <anlyUnit xml-lang="en">Individual <concept vocab="DDI Analysis Unit"
                        vocabURI="urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:AnalysisUnit:2.0">Individual</concept>
                </anlyUnit>
                <universe> Location of units of observation: Cross-national; National </universe>
            </sumDscr>
        </stdyInfo>
        <method>
            <dataColl>
                <timeMeth xml-lang="en">Cross-section <concept vocab="DDI Time Method"
                        vocabURI="urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:TimeMethod:1.2">CrossSection</concept>
                </timeMeth>
                <dataCollector> Intomart GfK (Hilversum, Netherlands) </dataCollector>
                <dataCollector> TNS Opinion </dataCollector>
                <sampProc xml-lang="en">Probability: Cluster: Stratified random <concept
                        vocab="DDI Sampling Procedure"
                        vocabURI="Probability.Cluster.StratifiedRandom"/>
                </sampProc>
                <deviat> 79,270 cases in total for both waves (35,634 in Wave Two and 43,636 in Wave
                    Three) </deviat>
                <collMode xml-lang="en">Face-to-face interview <concept
                        vocab="DDI Mode of Collection"
                        vocabURI="urn:ddi:int.ddi.cv:ModeOfCollection:3.0"
                        >Interview.FaceToFace</concept>
                </collMode>
                <weight>
                    <![CDATA[ The European Quality of Life Survey (EQLS) is a random probability survey of people aged 18 and over. The definition of the target of EQLS is the adult population (18+) living in private households. In order to be representative in terms of gender, age, urbanisation level, region and household size across all countries, three weighting coefficients were produced:<br> <ul><li>
    w4 - Final weight trimmed and standardised - this weight can be used for comparing any of the countries (both from EU and outside the EU) with each other and across different survey rounds (e.g. 2007 and 2011). However, this weight cannot be used to calculate an average for a group of countries.</li><li>
    w5_EU28 - Cross-national weight - EU28 - to calculate averages for all EU (as of 2013, that is including Croatia).</li><li>
    w5_total - Weight 5 total - a weight enabling any kind of grouping across different types of countries e.g. the Balkans, Nordic countries including Iceland or similar. However, because different countries were included in 2007 and 2011, it may not be possible to apply it for both years and the countries should be selected carefully.</li></ul>]]>
                </weight>
                <cleanOps>
                    <![CDATA[UK Data Archive Processing Standards<br><br>The data were processed to the UK Data Archive's A* standard. This is the Archive's highest processing standard. This means that an extremely rigorous and comprehensive series of checks was carried out to ensure the quality of the data and documentation. In addition, any data or documentation that breached confidentiality rules were altered or suppressed to preserve anonymity (see Privacy Impact Assessment statement above). <br> <ul><li>
Data: thorough checks were made to ensure the logical integrity of the data. The number of cases and variables were checked and verified with the depositor's records; all variables and values were labelled where possible; nominal (categorical) variables were checked to ensure that values fell within the range defined by value labels or in the documentation. </li><li>
Documentation: electronic and paper documentation supplied with this study has been incorporated into the UK Data Archive User Guide, in Adobe PDF format. The conversion programs used were the latest versions of Adobe Acrobat for electronic documentation, with any paper documentation scanned to .TIFF format and converted to PDF. The Data Concordance Grid is also supplied in MS Excel and CSV formats to allow subsetting and filtering. All PDF documentation files are fully bookmarked.</li></ul>]]>
                </cleanOps>
            </dataColl>
            <notes>
                <![CDATA[<br><b>Legal Agreement on Condition of Use</b><br><br>
In accordance with the depositor's wishes, these data were made open (no registration required). The UK Data Archive approved the decision to open the data.<br><br>
<b>Privacy Impact Assessment</b><br><br>
The UK Data Archive follows best practice guidance in the field of social science data sharing, taking its lead from the Office of National Statistics. Data owners and producers are responsible for signing off on confidentiality, following their own in-house protocols. For example, each government department may have its own classification system for data release of data and follow a bespoke standard. The Archive undertakes further routine checks on data to ensure the data meet our own confidentiality standards and match the type of licensing selected by the data depositor. Key survey variables are identified and checked for basic disclosure risk following the  <a href="http://www.ons.gov.uk/ons/guide-method/best-practice/disclosure-control-policy-for-social-survey-microdata/disclosure-control-guidance-for-microdata-produced-from-social-surveys.doc" target="_new" > UK Government Statistical Service (GSS) Disclosure Control Guidance for Microdata Produced from Social Surveys</a>. Release of other kinds of data, such as textual data, is approved by the owner/producer and is further checked by the Archive for disclosive information that may potentially be detrimental to meeting the original terms and conditions of the research and participant consent. The Archive follows the <a href="https://ico.org.uk/media/for-organisations/documents/1061/anonymisation-code.pdf" target="_new" > Anonymisation: Managing Data Protection Risk Code of Practice</a>.]]>
            </notes>
        </method>
        <dataAccs>
            <setAvail>
                <avlStatus> UK Data Service </avlStatus>
                <notes> &lt;a href=http://www.ukdataservice.ac.uk/help/get-in-touch.aspx
                    target="_new" &gt; Get in touch&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;These data are
                    available to any user for any purpose under the &lt;a
                    href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" title="Creative Commons
                    Attribution 4.0 International Licence (CC BY 4.0)" target="_new" &gt; Creative
                    Commons Attribution 4.0 International Licence (CC BY 4.0)&lt;/a&gt; </notes>
            </setAvail>
            <useStmt>
                <restrctn xml-lang="en">These data are available to any user for any purpose under
                    the &lt;a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/" title="Creative
                    Commons Attribution 4.0 International Licence (CC BY 4.0)" target="_new" &gt;
                    Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International Licence (CC BY 4.0)&lt;/a&gt; The
                    depositor has specified that registration is not required</restrctn>
            </useStmt>
        </dataAccs>
        <othrStdyMat>
            <relMat>
                <citation>
                    <titlStmt>
                        <titl> User Guide </titl>
                    </titlStmt>
                    <holdings URI="/ukda/related.jsp?guide&amp;sn=7724"/>
                </citation>
            </relMat>
            <relStdy>
                <citation>
                    <titlStmt>
                        <titl> For details of related publications and studies, please see: Data
                            Catalogue </titl>
                    </titlStmt>
                    <holdings URI="/ukda/related.jsp?sn=7724"/>
                </citation>
            </relStdy>
            <othRefs> Study Description: English; Study Documentation: Questionnaires are available
                both in English and in languages specific to the countries in which the survey was
                conducted. </othRefs>
        </othrStdyMat>
    </stdyDscr>
    <fileDscr URI="7724.Nesstar?Index=0&amp;Name=eqls_2007">
        <fileTxt>
            <fileName xml-lang="en" ID="F1">eqls_2007.NSDstat</fileName>
            <dimensns>
                <caseQnty>35634</caseQnty>
                <varQnty>196</varQnty>
            </dimensns>
            <fileType>Nesstar 200801</fileType>
        </fileTxt>
        <!--..........................-->
        <!--..........................-->
        <!--AND SO ON-->
    </fileDscr>
    <dataDscr>
        <var ID="V1" name="Wave" files="F1" dcml="0" intrvl="discrete">
            <location width="8"/>
            <labl> EQLS Wave </labl>
            <valrng>
                <range min="2" max="3"/>
            </valrng>
            <sumStat type="vald"> 35634 </sumStat>
            <sumStat type="invd"> 0 </sumStat>
            <catgry>
                <catValu> 2 </catValu>
                <labl> 2007 </labl>
                <catStat type="freq"> 35634 </catStat>
            </catgry>
            <catgry>
                <catValu> 3 </catValu>
                <labl> 2011 </labl>
                <catStat type="freq"> 0 </catStat>
            </catgry>
            <varFormat type="numeric" schema="other"/>
        </var>
        <!--..........................-->
        <!--..........................-->
        <!--AND SO ON-->
    </dataDscr>
</codeBook>
